Ellen Frank fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Ellen Frank fonds
1974 - 1984
F-82
Q102036486
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Frank, Ellen
Ellen Frank's interest in the women's movement began in 1972, while on a Kibbutz in Israel. At the time she was married, expecting her second child, and reading Betty Friedan's The Feminine Mystique. In April, upon return to Vancouver, Ellen Frank contacted the 'Woman's Centre' and became involved in a consciousness-raising group. Ms. Frank's involvement with the women's movement expanded from these beginnings. She became, in her words, "unmarried," and went to work at the Woman's Place. In addition, Ms. Frank also became involved in organizing around day care issues, came out as a lesbian, and worked around issues of violence against women. She also spent time organizing demonstrations, being active in occupations, and involved in the fight for women's rights in general. Ms. Frank passed away on January 30, 2017.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on its provenance.
Fonds consists of records created, received and collected by Ellen Frank in her involvement in the women's movement in Vancouver. Activities documented include participation in the Association of University and College Employees (AUCE), the British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW), the Solidarity Coalition, and activities relating to a number of other feminist organizations, issues, and actions. Includes correspondence, memoranda, minutes, agenda, reports, briefs, newsletters, press releases, notebooks, press clippings, project proposals, posters, and pamphlets.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Women; Labour
The fonds was donated by Ellen Frank.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Association of University Employees, 1979; F-82-1; 3 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the Association of University and College Employees (AUCE) and the 1979 strike at Simon Fraser University. Includes news bulletins, press releases, notebooks, and press clippings.
  Association of University and College Employees, Local 2
  - AUCE, 1979; F-82-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - AUCE - SFU strike, 1979; F-82-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - AUCE - SFU strike clippings, 1979; F-82-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
- British Columbia Federation of Women, 1975 - 1980; F-82-2; 5 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records of the British Columbia Federation of Women. The BCFW was an umbrella organization for women's groups in BC; its objective was to bring about women's liberation through fundamental social change. Includes project proposals, constitution, newsletters, minutes, regional reports, subcommittee reports, and correspondence. Also includes records relating to the Child-Care Interest Group and International Woman's Day.
  - British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW), 1975 - 1977; F-82-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW), 1977 - 1980; F-82-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW), 1977 - 1978; F-82-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - BCFW - Childcare interest group, 1975; F-82-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - BCFW - International Women's Day, 1980; F-82-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
- Solidarity Coalition, 1982 - 1984; F-82-3; 5 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the Solidarity Coalition. The Solidarity Coalition was formed in 1983 by concerned British Columbians who opposed the restraint policies of the Social Credit government. Includes lists of steering committee members, correspondence, agenda, minutes, reports, briefs, memoranda, resolutions, proposals, presentations, papers and posters.
  Solidarity Coalition
  - Solidarity Coalition - Provincial, 1983; F-82-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - Solidarity Coalition - Lower Mainland, 1983; F-82-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - Solidarity Coalition - Nov / Dec Assembly, 1983; F-82-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - Solidarity Coalition - Joint Committee, 1983; F-82-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - Solidarity Coalition - presentations, reports and miscellaneous, 1982 - 1984; F-82-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
  - Solidarity Coalition - miscellaneous, 1983 - 1984; F-82-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 82-1)
- Feminist organizations, actions and issues, 1974 - 1982; F-82-4; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files relating to a number of feminist organizations, actions, and issues with which Ellen Frank was involved. Files contain records on the Counselling Collective, Lesbians Against the Right, the Lesbian Caucus, the South Hill Childcare Society, Women Against Rape, and Women's Rally for Action. Includes correspondence, agendas, minutes, pamphlets, articles, newsletters, bulletins, and posters.
  Counselling Collective; Lesbians Against the Right; Lesbian Caucus; South Hill Childcare Society; Women Against Rape; Women's Rally for Action
  - Counseling Collective, 1974 - 1977; F-82-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - Lesbians Against the Right, 1979 - 1981; F-82-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - Lesbian Caucus, 1977; F-82-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - Lesbian Rights, 1977 - 1982; F-82-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - Manpower Demonstration, 1975; F-82-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - South Hill Childcare Society, 1975; F-82-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - Women Against Rape (WAR), F-82-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 82-2)
  - Women's Rally for Action, 1975 - 1977; F-82-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 82-2)